[Music]
hello and welcome to the junkyard love
podcast I listen to this morning um you
had an episode on your podcast I forgive
me I forget the name of um of the
episode but it was about like things
that helped with your depression and you
kind of shared like this weekend that
you did these things and and it happened
so I want to talk about all that sort of
stuff um just sharing what I kind of was
thinking in mind viewing your content
and stuff is um write write up my alley
so anything that you're going to say is
probably like perfect for my audience
and me anyway just keep that in mind um
and I also just like to do people who
are intentionally coming to stuff if
they're like oh this you know it has
depression in the title and I'm dealing
with depression that's pretty cool I'm
going to check that out and get better
whatever but I also really like the
newcomer I like involving people who
like the word depression grosses them
out to even say they don't really deal
with it maybe their like brother or
husband deals with it but it's a weird
thing to them so I want to include just
kind of everybody
so throw that out there keep it in mind
I I just uh I want to I don't want to
dumb everything down but I want to
include the newcomer to the stuff we're
talking about so those those are my
thoughts um and and I have a a list of
just pretty casual notes that I just
popped into my head as I was listening
to your stuff I'll reference them but
otherwise I love the back and forth I
can tell we're already just going to
Vibe out and and talk so perfect yeah no
thank you for thank you for having me
and it's so interesting you said about
the newcomer thing because
one of the things I was thinking about
today is the type of people I want to
work with the people who are like just
dipping their toe in and being like I
don't know how I feel about this but I
want to know more um so that's really
interesting that that came up because
that really resonates with me in terms
of being able to sort of open that door
gently without you know pushing in
people's faces yeah yeah do do you find
that um that that is where you you're
drawn to is like that that initial I I
feel like I'm drawn to kind of the
initial either the sudden Awakening or
like the sudden dude the way I've been
living is not working out for me I got
to change something and then like what
do you do there like what content do you
watch what book do you read I'm always
drawn to like that exact Catalyst what
about you are you entic I that's that's
interesting I guess the kind of people I
tend to attract the people who are sort
of noticing a shift within them but
haven't quite gotten into what it means
yet um not necessarily the sort of I had
a massive event and it's changed
everything for me type people but maybe
that's to come who knows um but the the
type of content that I enjoy I mean
similar to you anything anything
spiritual psychological emotional
well-being um just a researcher of life
and the soul and everything like that a
real truth Seeker you know um sort of
obsessed with always learning and I like
to work with people who are like that as
well you know what I mean who have got
that willingness whereas people who are
like will you do the healing for me no
no honey that's not going to work yeah
you got to take some responsibility for
your pain I'm so
sorry yeah it it is that thing on on on
the healing path is like there's this
brutal truth right at the beginning that
you really got to face it's like you got
to do the work like you like it's you
might think you're going to read a book
or find some answers or watch a YouTube
video and it's going to tell you exactly
how you're going to get held and
everything's going to be better but it's
it's really uh time to start tring
uphill is is what happens when you're
time to start healing so how did you
okay let's let's go back I feel like I
um I'm going to take us completely out
of linear time this whole this whole
episode I'm sure but uh um how did you
even get into this stuff initially have
you always thought like this have you
always been into um you know mental
health spirituality any of the things
that you're into now what is kind of
would you say is your initial intro to
it yeah I mean I think I've always been
into it when I was like the as young as
I can remember I had these in insane
dreams about a past I do past life
progression now so I know now that they
like it was a very important past life
for me and just kept having and kept
having them I was probably four or five
years old I don't know I remember saying
to my mom I I'm not normal I'm not I'm
very different to everyone else here I
don't fit in it doesn't feel right and
my whole sort of childhood really felt
like that I had quite a traumatic
upbringing and then when in 2019 sort of
a catalyst I think I sort of had chronic
trauma after trauma like the kind of
horrible real if you knew the kind of
stuff that has happened to me my body my
soul my mind you'd be shocked but it's
not stuff I need to like talk about so
much anymore because it's not now I'm
like oh look all the things that
happened for me great um but 2019 I
would say was like quite a pivotal year
for me I was in an abusive relationship
at the time I had early stage cervical
cancer I had massive issues with my womb
I've seven surgeries that year I had
postsurgical Amnesia I lost my entire
memory for 6 weeks like literally didn't
even know who I was my name friends
anything crazy and then my dog who was
like the my soul dog um went into to get
neutered get spayed and they forgot to
tie a tube and she literally bled out in
my arms the next day and it just broke
me and I think when you get to that
point where you're like I cannot I
cannot anymore um and I tried to take my
life that that that time in the UK we
have a suicide hotline called Samaritans
and I phoned them and you know this this
is what I'm going to do I just needed to
tell someone this is what I'm going to
do I was very much ready to go and and
he asked my name I Rebecca and he said
Brea where are you right now and I said
oh I'm just I'm on the floor in the dark
and he said will you just do one thing
for me that's what I'm going to ask he
said will you turn the light on and I
did and I stayed and then I was like you
know what I'm GNA go to Scotland on my
own for a week sleep in my car and I did
and I wait wait why why Scotland why did
you what was that I think I'd always had
like of calling to go um not really
knowing that it was like it's the
spiritual capital of the UK but I didn't
really know that so much I wanted to see
the stone circles and connect with that
kind of thing but I didn't know why I
guess I want to go I think I just wanted
to do something for me I was also very
into Outlander at the time have you seen
the Outlander series yeah yeah I was
like I'm gonna find Jamie he'll be
there that's so funny yeah so I I went
and then this little village called
killing I was like driving through and I
was like I'm not getting out of this
what I wanted to get out of this no one
spoken to me I was really hoping to have
that whole you know traveler experience
where people speak to when you meet new
friends and I was like exha fored I go
into this Pub in Killin and um sit down
at the bar to sort of sigh and the
bartender comes up to me was hello you
and it was as if we knew each other it
was really surreal sort of boost bumpy
now I know that we obviously knew each
other in a past life and that's why you
get that sort of sensation and then this
guy comes and sits next to me who's like
full traveler mode you know like in
traveler clothes big long beard wizard
Vibes um and I was like I'm going to
just talk to him he doesn't want to be
talked to but I did talk to him and he
was a bit irritated by at first and then
he said have you been to the stone
circle and I said oh what do you mean
which one um and it was a stone circle
in the village sort of you have to ask
the pub people it's sort of a bit hush
hush a little bit secret and we went to
this Stone Circle I ended up spending
the whole the rest of the evening with
him it didn't get dark in Scotland I
think half 11 at night at that point um
and he just talked to me about
spirituality and like Celtic mythology
and and just everything just kind of
went oh yeah this is what I've known my
whole life but somebody it's I'm not
just completely losing my mind this is
actually a thing um and since then it
has grown and grown that's a bit
longwinded but um I guess that's where
it really kicked off and now I'm
unstoppable with
it yeah that's so awesome wow that's so
cool um okay
so what was it I'm just so curious like
you went from this transition of you
know calling the suicide hotline that's
that's rock bottom right that's that's
like you I don't have I don't have will
to go on anymore this situation this
life that I've built for myself cannot
go any farther forward um and then how
so how many days was it like okay so
turning on the lights that was a huge
thing that sounds like that like when
they suggested that and then what was
the transition like how did you get out
of that curled up in a ball on the
ground type thing into you know what
let's make a move Let's Take Action cuz
I think that that's the big thing it's
like going from getting like getting up
off the floor is profound when you're
when you're that depressed you know so
what what happened there I think yeah so
Luna died February 13th 21 that year oh
no 2019 sorry um and then I think I went
in the May to Scotland so there was some
time where I planning but I guess you
know right about it's in my book when
you are at Rock
Bottom there's there's nothing there's
nowhere else to go so you can just sit
there and and then and then at one
moment there'll be like an arm that just
lifts up or or a leg or there's this
tiny tiny little spark within that's
like one more [__] try go on just do
it you know and it's like I think that
tiny little Slither of Hope was like
just this just one more just one more um
and I live like that for for a really
long time actually I've lived in living
in a in in an abusive relationship and
having had years and years of childhood
chronic trauma I was in that state of
survival mode all the time and I think
you get pretty good at dealing with
really horrible [__] um so I think in
that when everything just
absolutely got when you know all
happened so intensely at once that year
I think it was just a matter of come on
you're used to big things like this just
one more step one more minute one more
breath and then yeah unfolded that's
crazy it reminds me of I just it makes
me think of have you seen that movie um
hacksaw Ridge it's like an army movie
it's a this guy basically he like
refuses to carry a weapon the entire I'm
going on a Sidetrack this is not
important but he refuses to carry a
weapon the entire time it's like
something moral for him it's just a
value that he has everybody makes fun of
him but then this bad War happens and he
ends up like with no weapon he ends up
one by one dragging people's bodies to
safety um and he just keeps saying just
one more he he saves one life goes out
there with another gun without a gun
goes out there gets what just one more
just one more and just keeps do doing
its work so um that was such a stupid
tangent to go on I'm sorry it was I love
film references as well you got to keep
bringing in yeah it reminds me of that
though I I just love that I think that's
such a beautiful moment that like like
whatever that magic bit of hope that
that comes through that little speck of
light you know like I've had my own
experience with those where you're just
just done your brain's just cooked dude
you're you're like not loving yourself
you don't really see a way out and then
somehow there could be this little
sliver sliver of hope so so for me um uh
a thing that was really profound for me
when I finally made this transition was
almost this uh sudden like almost like
telling myself no in my head like I
almost had to like detach so I heard you
say something um in one of your podcasts
you basically I think you said um this
isn't me this is my nervous system or
something like you were basically like
separating you from your depressed
version of you um and uh I would love to
expand on that because I I did something
along those lines and it was really
profound for me to actually start
basically talking to myself and like
questioning these thoughts are coming up
and I'm used to be afraid of them I
didn't even want to face them but now
I'm like looking I'm staring them right
in the eyes and going no like this is
this is not working out I don't want to
do this I don't want to think like this
no I don't want to talk to myself stuff
like that know that's not helpful all
these sorts of things and it was very
very profound so I would love for you to
expand on what like what that looked
like for you cuz I love how you word it
is like this is my this is my nervous
system talking not me yeah I think it
can be so empowering to realize that you
are not your mental illness it's just
something that's happening to you right
now um You are so much more than that
and one of my favorite things that I say
is you are so much more than how you
think about yourself when you're afraid
because that fear just you know it can
dictate so much of how you live and
I think it's it's yeah it's so important
to be able to move away from that and
it's been a long long Learning Journey
for me um but that going back to sort of
that I guess Scotland Luna dying type
you know that horrible time I had that's
actually when I started my Instagram
account um well properly started it and
and what I decided I'm going to go on
this detox and I'm going to do Fitness
and I'm going to be accountable online
nobody's watching but I don't care this
is what I'm going to post and I guess
maybe it was there that the little the
little sort of shifts forward of how I
approached myself did give me confidence
because people would reach you know I
guess back in 2019 we weren't quite as
open even though it's not that long ago
it's still the way we've evolved as a
society about talking with about
feelings and things um I think people
was say oh Rebecca it's so helpful when
you write about this because this is
what I'm going through and then it was
like okay this is this is cool I can
talk about this and writing for me has
been so empowering and um so cathartic
and so healing and sort of going back to
what you're saying about how did I learn
to start talking to myself better
journaling writing was a big part of
that but also the community that I had
through Instagram and people hate on
social media but my little social media
friendships almost are really what made
me see that I was valuable and I was
worthy I didn't have that in my personal
in my real life if that makes sense and
I definitely used social media as a bit
of a crutch for me whilst I got through
2019 and then left my abusive
relationship
2020 and then you know really that
summer completely sort of really found
myself outside of the internet and and
on my own terms but yeah I guess that
was where that was how I started doing
it which is probably wouldn't work for
everybody I would recommend that for
most people right right okay so you
started just posting like like fitness
journey type stuff just holistic here's
here's what I'm going through like were
you cuz you're very um uh uh like
personal and welcoming and you're very
uh vulnerable in like such an elegant
way on on your social media now did it
start out like that for you or what was
it like when you started out yeah so it
it didn't start out as Fitness as per se
it started out as like a photo with the
essay underneath is what I still do now
which is like you know this is how I'm
feeling everyone in on the internet here
here's what's you know what I mean like
completely oversharing um and now I
process a little bit more before I post
things but it very much was just what
Journal you know this is my diary this
is my online diary and oh there's
actually people looking at this now and
then I'm I started doing the fitness
thing and posting a little bit more um
Fitness type stuff and people love a I
love a you know bikini pick or an ABS
pick and that obviously that then brings
different people in but I had um do you
know Kayla iten or it signs she's an
Australian Fitness um Fitness I don't
know what you'd call it influencer she
influencer is such a weird word but yeah
it's probably the best word yeah I don't
think I know I think I've heard of her
well she posted me on her story and then
I got like 10,000 followers overnight
and from there it just sort of snowball
a bit and then it stopped a few years
ago I haven't really had a big growth of
follower since and it's fine I don't
need that um anymore at all I'm
absolutely love where it is but no I
think I think really it's the personal
essays that is where I've sort of been
like oh cool I can have a voice for me
and that's okay and people kind of like
this side of me and now I can like this
side of me too yeah yeah the um dude the
I resonate so much with the you said
oversharing I think was a word you used
and I definitely have done that too many
times um but it's that's the crazy thing
about social media and um you know
podcasting and I even with all my
Artistic
Endeavors there's so stuff that I share
I mean over half the time there at least
maybe not when I post it but the day
after or a couple days after I rewatch
it I relisten and I'm just embarrassed
and it's just like this not only
impostor syndrome but you know there's
some level of cringe um I think that
just comes with the territory on social
media but I will say my older podcast
episodes like I started this in
and listening back like if you if you
strapped me to this chair and made
listen back to like some of my first 50
episodes it would just be excruciating
for me um but I'm so glad I did it
because yeah like I know it doesn't
Define me so it helps me grow in all
these ways I see all these ways that
I've just like learned how to conduct
myself in such a different way um I came
from a good place so that's like I don't
need to judge myself I was L just trying
to help people even if I said weird and
cringey embarrassing things or whatever
um and I think it sets the stage for and
you probably find this in your work when
you're vulnerable when you're honest
when you're authentic I I know it's like
such a overused word on podcast but it's
it's real when you're authentic it now
leaves room for them to be authentic it
it leaves the room so I shared my
traumas and stuff years back on on my
podcast and it's like sometimes I think
about I'm like I don't like those up
there it feels it feels vulnerable but
then people come on and they talk about
theirs and I'm like oh thank goodness I
you know I set the stage for real
authentic vulnerability I would I would
hate to have a guest come on and be open
and honest and feel embarrassed in any
way so um yeah I don't know I think like
a lot of the stuff that we share online
even though are personally it could feel
a little a little embarrassing I think
it's a net good and I think it's
encouraging people to like hey you don't
have to get 100 likes or be like a super
model or be like uh you know you don't
have to have six-pack abs to to post
something online it's I think it's for
everybody I think it's a it's a diary it
helps us it helps other people and it's
just it's a direct cleans into our real
selves you know it's social media is
pretty cool absolutely I think brne
Brown calls it a vulnerability hangover
and yeah that's the one um which it's so
interesting because like since I since
my fitness era um I don't do Fitness
anymore because I now have chronic joint
issues which means Fitness is not a
thing anymore sadly for me um but since
then I've had like my poetry era my
photography era my black and white era
um do you know what I mean like and I'm
it's very much just like a little bit of
an experiment now and I got to this head
space where I was like do you know what
this online account is my art gallery
and I can put up whatever I want in my
art gallery doesn't matter if anybody
else likes it or sees it it's just a
space for me and I'm very like is
nostalgic the right word I don't know I
quite like to go back and read through
how was you know how was 2018 Rebecca
how was and and I get to see exactly
what how I was processing what I was
writing and sometimes actually I did it
the other day I was like d i was good at
writing then that's cool you know and
when you write at the time you think oh
God that was awful and no one's going to
see it and no one's going to care and
you go back and you're like huh I like
that nice yeah yeah it's always
impressive have you ever had anybody
repeat back something that you've said
or written and you're like that's pretty
good they're like you you said that I
did
when yeah it's difficult when you've got
like I'm sure you'll feel was saying so
many creative Outlets like this is my
second podcast you know I've got
hundreds of YouTube videos that I've
been filming since I was 12 years old um
I've got hundreds of Instagram posts and
blogs and everything and I'm like I
don't even know what's on any of them
anymore like shortterm memory is not
that I know I uh I I think about like
that that period I was just mentioning
when I was first uploading episodes
whatever there's like a little bit of
cringe there's a there's also a lot at
the same time as the embarrassment
there's so much love for that version of
myself too like I I'm proud of that
version of myself you know paradoxically
all these things exist um but uh
um I think
back where was I going to go with
it apparently nowhere
profound um oh oh yeah that's what I was
going to say I think back to like when I
initially had because um a lot of like
my initial podcast episodes I was going
through like a profound Awakening and I
didn't freaking know that I really was
when I kind of did but like I didn't I
had a I
had it could be I I basically an an
unexpected Kundalini Awakening um when I
was
26 and I was not like spiritual I was
not trying to do any of that thing had
no idea what uh like it didn't wasn't
like someone who studied Enlightenment I
didn't meditate I didn't I just I
basically suddenly got into all this
stuff started doing a ton of meditation
ton of breath work ton of yoga smoking a
ton of weed so I was basically like this
like insane basic psychosis let's say of
to some extent um unawakening so it woke
a lot of beautiful things to me as well
but um anyway a lot of the content and
stuff I was making me having this artist
Alias is like really gives me in my mind
this excuse to like no dude you got to
be weird you got to push the edge you
got to push the boundaries and sometimes
some of the stuff that I put out I'm
like dude you're not going to have any
friends after this the stuff that you're
saying sometimes but um but I love that
that aie say that sounds that's that's a
very interesting way of looking at it
like it gives you that sort of
permission to play in that sense I think
there's something there's definitely
something to that there is so I I
experienced I was I started out my
artist thing was a
um I started out DJ Kronos with DJing
was basically the start of my thing and
then I always worked on my own art but I
didn't have so much of a everything kind
of felt like it got shuffled into DJing
and so I wanted to like make a name for
my art outside of my DJ name so I
actually came up with um around that
time I had like a new uh social media
artist DJ identity that I kind of
launched and it was just really cool um
obviously it's it's not a big deal to
anybody but me but it was super cool to
see how free my mind suddenly was like
there's I have all these bounds where
it's like these people have seen me at
shows they've like they know me as a DJ
and so anything I put out after like you
know like your Martin Garrick goes on
his social media page and starts talking
about Mental Health and be like you know
play some house music buddy what are you
like why are you talking about this so
it was kind of cool to like revamp and
and resend this new this new version of
myself and my Artistry but there's
something cool about social media when
it comes to that like seeing yourself in
a way that you maybe aren't right now
but you could be it really helps expand
us social media for creative and
spiritual people is so fun it's yeah
it's sick I agree I agree yeah um I took
us on a side quest there I'm sorry again
oh uh let's let's back up
so you've you've mentioned your your
chronic health issues a couple times um
in in some of the stuff that you went
through I want to kind of swoop up some
people who might be listening who maybe
are in those similar boats or they have
people around them who uh who might be
kind of lending an ear to whatever
they're listening right now so if you
don't mind would you mind kind of giving
me a general like so you had these
chronic things you have these like
abusive things happening to you and then
and you started to heal what did that
look like what did you do how how did
you face it before you even started
healing I'm just super interested in all
of it yeah so in terms of healing do you
mean like the emotional
healing yes and uh of course I'm always
really fascinated with that like initial
like how did you finally start facing it
or admitting that it was real that it
was um something that um didn't Define
you
um yeah so I think like leaving my
abusive relationship ended a long cycle
of me being squashed by people bigger
than me and me thinking that was very
normal um and I think 2020 for me and I
feel guilty saying it was the best year
of my life um
because I literally took myself out on
dates I went for walks I you know when
we locked down obviously was a bit
different but I still was going going
for walks I moved to the ocean um I was
on my own I just
completely immersed into my own space of
who am I and there's something in my
book as well I talk about dating
yourself and I have this list that's
called the Getting to Know Yourself list
so it was literally like when you meet
somebody for the first time you want to
know every little thing about them every
time you work every weird thing they do
every little Hobby and habit and I was
like why have I never done that for me
so for example a couple of things on my
list is like I love to watch the end
credits of films I don't know why I do
it but I do um I always sniff milk when
I open a milk I always sniff it and it's
just something I do habitually I don't
know why it happens um other things I
learned loads of different music that I
didn't really like so like classical
piano music as well as like Disney and
pop so um it's like fun stuff like that
where I'm like oh who is this cool
person I get to know and I get to
discover about and like oh I don't
actually like this thing and I love
wearing tight clothes and I shouldn't
feel guilty for that and it's fine that
I do it's actually a lot to do with
oxytocin that gets released from
pressure to the skin but a little
science fact for you there um so I think
it was a matter of literally dating
myself and I absolutely swear by that um
in giving yourself time and that's why I
think that everybody needs to be
intentionally single for at least some
part of their life to know themselves I
really really believe that yeah yeah I
mean some people never ever have that
that that experience some people are
dating uh you know since middle school
and they never really go through go
through any sort of breakup that's
always insane to me how so do you think
this was born you clearly were spending
time with yourself in this in this
instance right like was that were you
with friends were you on your phone a
lot or were you actually like spending
time with with yourself it sounds like
just with myself and Taylor Swift
actually a hell of a lot oh
damn I I was doing like this is went
before my health got really bad and I
was walking like 5 miles a day I was
working out like crazy um so exercise
and walking and then I'd be on this
beach I would just sit on the beach and
I would just be listening to I can't
remember which album was Taylor Swift
had released like the year before or
something but really just remember that
being very poignant in that for that
year for me um I think maybe folklore
maybe that was around that year I don't
know but um yeah and so that was the the
coral element and then when lock down
who released and stuff and I moved back
home I did a a load of sort of moon
rituals that was became a very big part
of my identity in the sort of
spirituality side really flooded in then
um did some path life work did some
medit you know got into meditation then
got into yoga then so it was yeah very
much intentionally within and then also
the communication through Instagram and
things but more more with myself and and
I think journaling and I was making a
lot of like Tik toks then being again
bit cringey but like seriously honest
about like I'm having a really terrible
day or I'm dancing in the shower today
with my clothes on because I can um you
know and it was just it was almost like
the thing that kept me going was just
keep randomly posting and and as
something might take yeah yeah I I I
like that there's something about
posting on social media that's so
freeing um as much as it has its own
self- constrictions it can be so freeing
like you think you know something about
me you didn't know I could do this you
know it's it's fun um it's it's very
interesting too and I love all the
different uh because like you found me
on threads are you active on threads
often I don't think I dove too deeply on
your threads it was mainly your
Instagram I think I've like I go on
threads just very occasionally and just
sort of stalk on there a little bit say
what's going on but I haven't really I I
still find thread a little bit scary it
reminds me too much of Twitter which
frightens me a bit dude Twitter is just
insane nowadays I can't even I I get
sucked into it and I have to snap out of
it and go dude get off your phone cuz
I'll be watching like I'll be just oh
let's check out what's going on you know
let's see what elon's crazy ass has to
say today and then suddenly I'm like
watching my 18th video of high schoolers
fist fighting and I'm like whoa dude
what am I doing like why am I why do I
watch that right now I have so many
other things I could be doing um but
it's like that but I like
the there's like a flavor like a scent
to all social media in in a sense you
know um and I find that fascinating
threads has an interesting one I joined
it just at the beginning just poking
around when they first announced it and
then I started kind of just like sharing
some random poems on there um started
following a couple poetry accounts and
if you if you're active on there quite a
bit and consistent of course they you
know go figure they reward someone who
sits on their phone all the time uh but
it does start bringing you to to other
people like I had a few months where
most days I had like back and forth
conversations with other poetry people I
would share poems people would like
comment their poems in response like it
was just this fun poetry party for for
many months on there and I just like I
don't think you could get that on
Twitter maybe it's not a world I'm I'm
into on Twitter but um there there's
more High School fist fights on on my
Twitter feed than there is poetry
so um but yeah so
um posting on social media you were
posting on social media what was the
last thing that I asked do you remember
um Jacob I have a terrible short-term
memory so I know I'm the host I'm the
one who's supposed to remember I'm like
you start talking about things that
excite me so I'm like let me let me
mention that you were talking we were
talking I remember I talked about tlor
Swift um and about you asked me about
was I on my own was I on my phone when I
was doing the healing work there go
right yeah and then you gave me a blank
space where my mind used to be jlor joke
um sorry uh okay so so yeah so the
reason why I asked about that is
like I the amount of people
that like you probably experience it
like you get into an Uber or you go into
a gas station or a grocery station the
amount of people that like are always
either on the phone or they're always
listening to something and I'm I'm
guilty of definitely like I I love
listening to podcast or or an audiobook
or whatever like I'll go grocery
shopping with a headphone in but it's
invaluable for me to remember oh yeah I
need some time with just me with no
headphones I don't need to scroll
through social media right now I even
did it last night I had realized oh all
day I've just been pulverizing my brain
with info that I think is super
important so I went for a walk last
night and took my headphones out and
realized by the end of my walk like dude
my body is just so much more calm just
from taking my headphones out um so can
you speak
on like the importance of spending a
little bit of time truly alone I would
love to emphasize that yes so actually
I've just been on a solo trip to
Thailand as you know as everybody can
see on my Instagram because it's there
every single day and I'm sick of the
content now too but something it really
taught me because I had no internet I
turned my phone to internet free like
the entire time basically and turn it on
for 10 minutes the internet on 10
minutes a day let my loved ones know I
was still alive and that was pretty much
it um and what it taught me that there
was like well Rebecca your phone is
distracting you from all of your
potential we need to thought this out
and I'm quite a disciplined person so
once I'm like this is what we're going
to do I will do it so so actually since
I've been back which I came back mid
December and it's now January 8th I have
had my phone set up I don't know if you
use the focus modes on your on do you
have iPhone yeah yeah yeah so the focus
modes I've set up a custom one and I
called it Hol day and I can't access
Instagram so I can't social media um
WhatsApp anything I can only access text
from my immediate family which I don't
get text from that often and my
boyfriend that's it so I basically don't
have my phone on weekends I don't have
my phone on past 6:30 p.m. in the
evenings so I forced myself to have solo
me time and then weekends is if because
if I don't have my phone there you know
how you mentioned earlier about W that
when the creativity flows in when you
had that sort of Instagram Alias that's
almost like what it is for me without my
without the internet so I think I said
to you the other day on Instagram I was
like I'm terrible at replying on here
because I'm barely on Instagram anymore
because I'm I schedule everything so I'm
not actually on there people think I'm
people are messaging like oh Rebecca
just I will reply in three days when I
come back on um so it's forced me to be
in that space with myself and now that
I'm used to it I actually hate having my
phone on I'd like rather have it off I
never thought I'd get to that space But
I have um and just having time with me
now is so critically important that I I
just I'm so glad that I really fully
made that step from like a strict
discipline point of view and um and went
into that space because there's so much
to gain I mean I'm a meditation junkie
and I will sing it from the hilltops um
but that is you know without without
having that that time where I allocate
this is no phone time this is dedication
to the self to the soul to reading to
learning to growth and to writing my
books or writing courses or whatever is
my creative projects are um yeah without
that I wouldn't be making any progress I
wouldn't be growing so yeah yeah I mean
we're we're complete you know everybody
says in some sort of way we're such
guinea pigs for these phones you know
it's like I think it's 2007 or 8 2007 I
think the iPhone came out I mean that's
not that long ago that's pretty crazy
it's like everyone's entire lives now
you know so um like being Simon cynic
talks about he's a like a leadership
motivational teacher guy you may have
heard of him but um he he this thing he
comes out on stage he had this opening
like motivational talk or whatever and
he had his phone in his hand and he was
basically talking like as he's talking
with his hands and it's just in his
hands he's not using it then he points
out like you guys notice my phone's in
my hand the whole time and everybody's
like yeah we notice and he's like that's
a percentage of your attention you know
like like if if if I don't just put this
thing fully away in my pocket there's
like some level of distraction not only
for me but for you guys as you're
talking to me like if you're talking to
someone and they're like occasionally
glancing down at their phone like every
every time they glance down it's a loss
of con connection with the person that
that you're talking to um and I think
that we're like we got to implement our
own boundaries with our phones because
like it's a bright colorful magical
Casino box of awesome like it hey do you
want to look at a video of anything you
ever wanted like cool cuz it's in your
pocket you know like it makes sense that
we're addicted to the dang things but um
yeah it's it's super important I found
that you know along these worlds of of
like healing from depression mental
health meditation um you know leaking
into like the self and identity as far
as I'm
concerned I think many people are
unknowingly radicalized by their phone
and um I think that
like you could
be like the things that are super
important to to to us in our day-to-day
lives have changed because of our phones
and I think that your phone could be
telling you all day this is important
this is the most important and there's
part of your identity that will latch on
to that
and then suddenly you're spending seven
hours like with your with your mind into
your magic rectangle here and you're not
living your life you know like you're
not like actually interacting with with
the people around you you know like
there's there's just cause there's there
is things that are like important to to
to care about you can't just bury your
head in the sand for everything but I
just feel like it's so important it
seems like such a low hanging obvious
fruit to just hey man is really as
important put your phone in the other
room sometimes set limits on your phone
set the um I like how you did it too
Rebecca because often what what we'll
hear I don't know if you hear this is
people like dude I can't I just want to
go to a flip phone I just want a flip
phone I want to get rid of this iPhone
and that like would make life pretty
difficult to navigate sometimes you just
need GPS whatever but I like you're
smart about it it's like you set limits
you stick to them so so you have it go
off at a certain time like it's what you
say like 6:30 at night you don't have
anybody responding to you yeah I think
those are super helpful um in your world
of like coaching and dealing with other
people's mental health is this a big
deal for people is this something that's
like profound for you to point out to
them um is is this something that you
would recommend for a lot of people is
like hey man really become aware of what
you're consuming on your phone I think a
lot of people don't see it as a problem
um I think that people use it and and
there's definitely a place for this we
use all kinds of distractions to numb
ourselves from feeling pain from feeling
suffering um and that's a whole topic
that we can go into I'm reading Fab book
on that the minute called the road L
travel by Scott PE I don't if you've
read it um it's brilliant um it talks
about avoiding suffering but I think
from a point of like the phone thing so
one of my big unhealed or unworked
through triggery spaces is around food
and around I think I did actually I've
got a couple of reals out on Instagram
about this my Thailand trip um I I
really wanted to force myself to sit
with my food and eat my food without
being on my phone or reading a book or
being distracted or watching TV big one
for me um so one of my extra rules as
well as my phone boundaries is I have to
have one present meal a day which is
where I sit with nothing with no one
with just my food no phone and I just
sit and eat my food and it's scary and
it makes me uncomfortable and there's
little my eating disorder voices around
and I'm like that's interesting hey nice
to see you you know being The Observer
again to those kind of things um but it
is like I I think people don't see it as
a problem and you have to have the break
from it to realize that it is a problem
you know what I mean I probably didn't
see how big a problem was for me to I
was in Thailand and I had that real two
and a half week break from my phone and
I was like wow I am I am completely
myself without it and when I'm with it
it takes away a little part of me um as
well as you know both you and I have
said we love the the option to be
creative online but it has to come with
boundaries and it has to come with the
space of still being able to be yourself
outside of your phone um so yeah I I
mean it's definitely an issue I just
don't think people realize how big an
issue is until you
stop yeah for real yeah it's it's
definitely a the way that the algorithms
are are made now as well is like if
you're not careful you suddenly the tool
that we have here like the tool is using
you if you're not careful in this weird
way like in this very confusing kind of
never before like it's new to our
species to have something that like like
the tool takes away our attention from
from the you know Perce CE purpose of it
initially have you read dopamine Nation
CU she talks about it in that book quite
a lot dopamine Nation who who wrote that
do you remember I feel like I've heard
of it yeah it sounds like a familiar
term anyway I I I haven't read it but I
think I have heard of it it's good from
a point of realizing that actually there
is an addictive element to the phone use
it's not completely all me because I'm a
big fan of but take a little bit of the
resp responsibility away from you not
all of it a little bit away from because
there so there's always other factors
involved and sometimes you you know life
is too big and you need a distraction um
but the addiction part is is so so real
yeah do you um uh there's a podcast do
you listen to Chris Williamson from
modern modern wisdom yeah I love his
podcast yeah yeah he he lives in Austin
now I'm pretty sure actually we go to
the same haircut person so I am sure
that he yeah um fun fact uh he he has
this thing that I loved when I heard it
he said it uh it was just a couple
months ago he basically said there's
there's a dopamine Chris and there's
like an oxytocin Chris and he just like
he just tries to become really aware of
like what version of himself is is he
feeding or like feing for or whatever
and since he said that I try to notice
that in myself and I I you know just by
noticing it doesn't mean that I I solve
it for sure sometimes I'm very aware
that I'm having just a dopamine Jacob
day and I'm just you know just it is
what it is you know but the awareness is
helpful like okay I'm just trying to
like get a hit okay I got done with that
thing and like I'm really itching to eat
food right now even though I just ate so
I notice okay I'm just trying to get
that dopamine hit and I'm actually not
really Desiring these things as much so
um hey what was that uh I want to back
up what was that book that you mentioned
that you're reading so I'm reading the
road I think it's called The Road Less
travel by Scott peek about suffering you
said yeah so it's written 70s it's
written in the 70s and he talks about
like one of the biggest the biggest like
challenges that we have as humans is
that we think pain and suffering is this
terrible awful thing that we each run
away from whereas actually it's the cast
list for growth and you'll Lally won't
go anywhere without it um and so much of
the culture that we're exposed to is how
to suffer less and how to be happier and
how you know actually actually and I
think you and I had a brief chat about
the power the book The Power of Now by a
cart in terms of him saying well
actually there's no such thing as any
good or bad because it's all for your
growth it's all for your development um
and sort of sidetracking linking this in
when I got to my Thailand trip I was
like whoa I feel so guilty for this I'm
in a five-star result I shouldn't be on
this holiday I feel awful I should be
doing I should I haven't suffered hard
enough to be here I haven't worked hard
enough to be here and I S of realized
like maybe a week in I was like huh but
I'm learning so much from this
experience that it's almost there's
almost suffering in the learning and
isn't that fascinating and I was like
and then reading the book at the same
time the Power of Now book and thinking
that it doesn't matter whether we
perceive it as humans as good or bad
it's here to give us growth and I think
we just need to really lean into that
and be with the suffering and be with
the pain um and then there's there
there's a difference between and Liz
Gilbert who wrote Eat Pray Love and big
magic she talks about this as well big
magic is so good sorry to interrupt so
good especially I think for creatives
it's like oh it's like an such Alchemy
in there it gives me chills as I'm I
listen to un audible it gives me chills
like multiple times it's so good she my
idol she's I dedicated my last book to
her um but it's talking about the um
losing my train of thought here sorry
big big magic it's fine it was worth it
it was worth it
um pain of suffering
versus come on
Rebecca do you remember where I was I'm
supposed to be helpful for this part too
dude
I I I do the same thing um you were kind
of just giving me like a summary of the
book it was talking about suffering um I
think you're kind of talking about how
people typ see suffering go Liz Liz
Gilbert talks about depression being
different to to pain and depression
being like stagnation of pain um and and
grief being movement through of pain um
in terms of and I really relate to this
in my own in personal grief and you know
I've lost a baby I've lost dog my best
friend died um and then seriously bad
breakups that kind of thing and the pain
you that I feel when I'm geving it's
it's like awful and you rock bottom but
it also you sort of know that you're
moving through it it's this really I
don't know if anybody else experiences
this but it's this really weird state of
like Comfort I feel with grief when I
lost my baby I was like this is the
worst thing ever but also I feel so at
peace with this whereas when I've been
in depression I'm like this is the worst
thing ever I don't know if I can survive
this I think I'm going have to the only
way out is to die it's the only I can do
um but that's because there's like a
stagnation of that suffering because I'm
not allowing myself to actually work
with it I'm just resisting it lot of the
time because you can't see any other way
and a lot of that is biological um
another book recommendation is probably
recommendation number 60 so far of this
podcast is change Your Brain Change Your
Life which again totally altered my
perception of my mental health is not
the same as who I am um and my brain
isn't wired right because I had really
serious Early Childhood trauma and
that's okay so let's figure out how to
work a life around that and be a bit
more gentle with myself about how I you
know how I work my life and that it's
different to other people and that
that's okay um and and yeah I guess
sorry tangent there but I think pain and
suffering is a fascinating concept yeah
no well summarized there too that's I
feel like if I was listening I would
just definitely want to dive into that
book and if I remember I say this often
sometimes I forget I will try to include
every book that was mentioned in an
Ideal World I like to mention it in in
include the link down below so fun day
with this one I know I'm listening back
and then I get sidetracked so I'm like
well maybe I need a copy of that book
and then suddenly I'm look looking for
the book and I'm not eding um but yeah
dude I I think the the line I'm always
really fascinated I think Buddhism and
stoicism that they talk about like
suffering and acceptance acceptance is
that's that's been like one of the
biggest lessons for me is realizing how
often in my life that I've made things
worse by not accepting it by not working
with what's really going on because I'm
I'm actively like I'm trying to form
some identity in that moment of being
the victim the sufferer you know and and
just how freeing it really is to just
how impossible sometimes and it's
actually hilarious how impossible is
sometimes when you notice like there I
am freaking so ticked off that things
aren't going my way but what am I going
to do you know and you're like laughing
at how mad you are I don't know if you
ever get to those experiences but it
really is a it's a powerful tool and
it's something that I I find that a
meditation practice is like one of the
biggest helpful things ever because it
said you know that line between stimulus
and response it it it expands that Gap
to where like you you notice okay here's
a bad thing that's happened and here I
am complaining about it here I am like
uh trying to text all my friends about
it I'm trying to make a video for social
media about it I'm trying to be like
look what happened to me whatever
actively making it worse you know and so
it's it's a it's a profound thing so I
would love for you to speaking to
someone right now who this might be
something that they don't really deal
with like I'm trying to think of myself
back when I first started exploring this
sort of stuff and realizing oh I'm
making myself the victim I'm making
things worse than they have to be what
is kind of the magic there what is I
mean obviously the initial awareness
right like noticing when you're when
you're having those conversations with
yourself or you're stacking it on
yourself or you're noticing um even like
you said like you're identifying
yourself with your mental health you're
identifying with your thoughts um what
what do you what comes up in in in your
conversations with uh with with clients
and people that you talk to in in that
realm like that initial that initial
first
noticing I think one of the tricks that
I definitely have is take notice of the
things that really piss you off whether
that's you know um there's this
psychologist who post things online that
used to really trigger me about
basically taking responsibility for your
your [__] and I was like no she doesn't
know what I've been to she doesn't how
bad it was for me that's not you know
and and now I look at it and I laugh
because I'm like I see I see and so
taking notice of the things that tick
you off because I think that's a really
good space for you to actually have a
good chat with yourself self-reflection
obviously is like the the big key um and
I think a way to really and being wrong
and being okay with being wrong and I
think a really good way that I practice
this is within my own interpersonal
conflicts so something I'm very very
good at doing is if I'm having if
somebody's light back I really didn't
like how he did that I'll sit and okay
um and I'll reflect back you know so you
didn't like how I put my shoes away
whatever it is um and then they go yeah
yeah I didn't like that and I'd be like
okay you know what I I was really messy
I see how I was really messy now yeah
that was actually just really lazy of me
I don't know why I did that and I will
just be like brutally upfront honest in
that situation and it feels like really
like Li rating I'm like wow I did
something wrong and I admitted it that's
so cool I think it often comes I don't
know I this is like my bro science
theory for talking modern wisdom um
lingo here but I don't know if it comes
from people who couldn't get things
wrong as a kid I definitely couldn't get
anything wrong as a kid um so maybe like
as an adult admitting that you've got
flaws can sometimes feel really scary um
more than just uncomfortable but scary
because maybe you know subconsciously
you're thinking what what are the
consequences for me um your subconscious
is still tapped into childhood stuff you
know there like like I said there's
always a space for um an external Factor
playing a part in the way we behave but
yeah self-reflection is is big and I
think my little Moon rituals which is
let's say it's like two hours on a full
moon or a new moon of me just sitting
with my journal with like really Trippy
Music on and like purple lights um and
like some kind of incense or something
and I'll be like writing like um
questions for myself hard-hitting brutal
truth telling questions that I'm like
don't want to answer this doesn't feel
right I don't like it um it is just
having to be super duper honest and it
and I think being okay with being wrong
being okay with making mistakes and not
being perfect that's fine yeah yeah uh
yeah be being okay with making mistakes
is actually like seems like such a
simple sentence but how often are we not
okay with like okay [__] I did that and
now I gotta now I got to deal with it
you know it's like or we defend what we
did uh we we jump in we're like well I
did that because when I was 10 my dad
did this and you know and it's and it's
and a lot of that stuff can be very true
and it could also be like right there
like you don't have to remove it you
don't have to deny it but it's also you
know so what are you goingon to do make
it worse well like who who's going to
take care of this besides you you know
yeah so it's it's just this summer just
gone had like a real beautiful um
meditation type experience I really
believe that if you do a 45 minutes
medit 45 minute meditation it has the
same power of a psychedelic trip I just
I really stand by that I will die on
that Hill um but I had this sort of
experience over summer where I was
really dragging myself through this this
pain cycle right I um I've been sober
since 2021 I relapsed at the beginning
of summer this year 2024 well we last
year now um
and I sort of got into this real nasty
place with it where I for for probably
six weeks I was like I'm this terrible
person I've failed I [__] up at
everything um you know it's it's his
fault it's you know you shouldn't have
said that and that wouldn't have
happened and I just got myself into this
real fun it's fascinating to experience
fascinating and then I get into my real
deep in this when I really said no we're
committing to meditation now I'm not
[__] around with this um so I'm then
doing 45 minutes twice a day and I come
out of this thinking I can choose not to
suffer about this huh that's so cool I
can choose to just let all of this go
today and I literally did it was like an
overnight thing I actually filmed a
podcast the day after it happened um and
I was like in this podcast I'm like wow
I can't believe what just happened to me
it was amazing um so it is very much
really forcing yourself to do the work
sitting with it admitting that you
[__] up and then moving on you know
yeah yeah that's um it's so crazy what
meditation can do sometimes it's it
really I mean it's it's a pretty just as
as a base statement even somebody who
doesn't really meditate that much it's
pretty easy to imagine kind of like okay
so you're sitting there crisscross
applesauce um is that a term that you
guys had in the UK actually with Cris
cross I love it that's so funny I said
it I was like you probably don't know
yeah that's a in elementary school like
you sit down you cross your legs
crisscross applesauce I no idea why we
said it but
um American lingo um but anyway so okay
so like you're sitting in the meditation
you know close your eyes open them
whatever sitting crisscross applesauce
and then you can imagine yourself from
the from the Eagle's Nest right the
30,000 point view like I think most
people can sit down and they can kind of
like imagine themselves in in in that
moment
um
uh the like the freedom
of like you're sitting there you are the
one meditating right so like how are you
all able to see a view of yourself from
above like that alone I think is pretty
like and you could really manipulate
that and and work with that as you
meditate but just what I'm talking about
is like just the separation again like
the initial separation from you're
sitting there a second ago you could be
thinking all these things and suffering
like you're you know replaying the past
or whatever it is um or you're thinking
about the future and you're you're
stressed about that anxiety versus
depression you
can as a third option BAS basically
observe that that's going on from like
the 30,000 point uh view the metac
conscious like you can see yourself
doing that and I
think
people having that as an option like
just like that little bit of practice is
such an Open Door um it's such a like
a a room for possibility um and what I
wanted to uh I was I was trying to more
elegantly weave that in um but I wanted
to ask you
about how do I simplify this basically
here's how we'll do it if someone who
doesn't meditate but they're depressed
they're listening right now like they're
depressed they've got it they've got it
this far they're watching this clip
whatever the heck it is but they're
depressed and they've tried meditation
and they've said I can't meditate I'm 2
ADHD um that's always our that's that's
a meditation teacher favorite uh
response uh or you know I'm not my mind
is too crazy or they sit down in like
their own mind terrifies them so you
know we we all have that version of it
too I've experienced that myself um we
sit down to meditate and we're trying to
like heal our depression I'm throwing
that ball into your court Rebecca what
does that have to do with anything like
how does me meditating and sitting still
cure my
depression yes oh my gosh I'm so glad
you asked me this because I really
wanted to input here that one of my big
triggers almost from you know what I was
saying earlier was people being like Oh
just meditate and you'll be fun he be
like suck off like like leave me alone
go away with your meditation [__] um
and I am very neur diversion as you can
probably tell by how fast I talk and my
meditation does not look anything like
how I thought it was supposed to and yet
it still has these incredible effects so
I'm not even [__] you I will sit 45
minutes and my brain will just be
talking about what I'm going to do to
the front garden next year and how I'm
going to plant this and what you and
literally that is and I will be
frustrated with myself with within it
sometimes and being like come on you
know just do some breathing and I'll
have a couple minutes where I do and
then it won't and then but but now I'm
absolutely fine with that I run with it
because it works for me um and I I know
proper meditation teachers even though I
am one on insight timer um proper but
would say well that's not real
meditation and I'm like no maybe not
it's mindfulness more than anything but
what it is is me sitting with myself and
how often do you get to do that on your
busy crazy life now how often do you
take that time um so I am very strict
with myself now again insight timer does
really help they have like I don't know
if you use insight timer but they have a
um a streaks feature now which for
somebody who's neurod Divergent is
really addictive so I'm like I am not
missing a day um so that means that I
will go on for one minute and meditate
if that is what it takes one minute of
deep breathing and and that is that is
enough um and it's not you know for me
you you got to get into doing it as
regly as you can even if it's one minute
day and you may not notice a difference
for 3 months but you will be like hey
I'm spending time with myself that is a
really loving thing for me to do and
that that that little moment there that
is where the difference is look at this
loving thing I did for myself um and
again it's is a part of this in my book
where it's like hey I made myself
breakfast today look at how loving that
was hey I had a shower today look at how
loving that was that was something that
you did for you and it may seem like
it's just a habitual thing that you're
supposed to do but you could have you
could have not done that you could have
stayed a bed all day but you didn't um
you made that choice to love yourself
even if it was for one minute or if it
was 45 minutes and if your brain talked
at you the whole time you were
meditating you still showed up to
yourself and that is where that slow
healing that slow beginning to love
yourself again comes in just in little
tiny tiny little pieces and you can do
it a way that works for you like there's
no read doesn't have to be so much
structures like keep your brain calm and
don't have any extra thoughts like I
just don't believe in that at all and
I've been doing for a long time and it's
giving me these insane insights usually
the morning after I meditate is when I
get these incredible creative um or
alchemistic type like Soul events um is
usually the morning after a really long
meditation or whenever I really do it to
be honest but um yeah it doesn't have to
be the way that I think people think it
has to be if that makes sense no it
totally does I I mean i' the biggest
thing that I'm always fighting with
people um not fighting with people but
just like my initial ah well you might
have misunderstood uh uh my smartass
response when people are like I I I
can't like I can't I just can't stop my
thoughts I'm like well you're not
supposed to stop your thoughts like it's
it's okay to have thoughts you know um
and that alone like that it's funny so
many people have this misunderstanding
about meditation I suppose I probably
did at the beginning too like a lot of
times these people are saying these
things on the on the guided meditations
and my understanding of them was like I
don't what do you what do you mean mean
like what do you
like your thoughts and like it just
takes a while to kind of develop really
even just the art of stepping away from
your sticky thoughts and like just
looking at them from over here like that
takes a little bit of meditation
sometimes to even notice so yeah anybody
who's like starting out meditation if
you sit down and you're I don't get it
it doesn't make sense for me do what
Rebecca said like one minute is
profoundly better than zero minutes and
your minute doesn't have to be
completely still your minute doesn't
have to be like you could be freaking
wiggling around the whole time but are
you like noticing what you're doing are
you becoming aware of of you know your
senses your thoughts are you aware that
you're in the room um so often we have
this momentum I always notice this when
I go for
walks my practice walking is how quickly
can I notice that I've just been like
let's go I'm A to B I'm at a destination
and then suddenly I'll notice and I'm
like why am I walking fast dude I'm on a
nice walk I don't need to be anywhere
I'm just walking you know and and
meditation helps you notice like you
have this momentum of running everywhere
with your personality and suddenly you
go oh I can I can relax I could I could
chill out I don't have to like be trying
to arrive somewhere all the time I could
just like OB observe what's going on I
could just sit back into into what's
what's really
happening what's um so what what was
your journey with meditation like when
when did you first start meditating um
in what uh I know like the the
terminologies don't really matter but
like what do you find is your common um
teaching style like do you teach
mindfulness do you teach um like a a
different and and also I'm sorry I'm
throwing another question in there what
works for people who aren't used to
meditating I love getting people who
don't meditate at all maybe they've
tried it it doesn't work for them I love
getting them like to try something else
you know maybe it's breath work maybe
it's a different type maybe it's uh you
know some yoga before so so what helps
people and how did you um initially get
into it okay so I think I started
meditation probably I was about 12 or 13
um there's a monastery near me which I
will go to sort of occasionally I used
to go to quite a lot um but now as when
I go now I'm like I just don't I don't
Vibe with the way that you talk to us
anymore actually um it's I've learned a
lot about um Buddhism and I I was a
Buddhist for a year but I don't think I
really knew it as I know it now um and I
don't know that I align with it in the
same way that I did and that's okay um
but I've tried so many different types
of meditation I think that's something
that's so important for people to know
is that it's not just one thing um there
are you know Z meditation is the choir
of the mind which is a very Buddhist way
of teaching things and being physically
completely still which does not work for
somebody you like me um I was at the
monastery recently and my hips now will
I have EDS so they will dislocate if I
am in the wrong position for too long
basically and I had to keep moving and
the monk kept her me off and I'm like oh
I can't tell you but if if we carry on
like this I'm going to be there's going
to be an
ulated my hip uh can
we like no don't move um so it's like
disate the other one and sit still let's
see deal with accept the suffering
accept the
pain that's very much one end of the
spectrum um and the other end is like
literally walking meditations um
mindfulness you know so cooking I think
is a great one if you can cook and be
totally with the food and totally with
the Motions of your hands cutting the
onion or whatever it is um I think
that's such a crucial space for you to
just again being with yourself being
with the moment being present I think
tips I would use is like I think insight
timer is amazing and I know that I work
for them but also there's so much on
there I think if you haven't tried it
David G and it's spelled David ji um is
fantastic and his body scan is one that
helped me through a severe episode of
anxiety for me because I was just with
him with his voice with my body um and
that I was just I played that I think my
longest day I played it for eight hours
straight my statistics said um when I
was having a really really bad time
bless bless previous me um so I think it
yeah find I think in is great find a way
that works for you and and have wiggle
room with it and have a little bit of
fun doing it you know it's not oh I have
to meditate because people said it would
make me feel better be like I'm choosing
to meditate I don't know how it's going
to work for me yet um I don't know if
it's going to be actually just 20
minutes of me stretching and in silence
or or whether it's going to be me sat
listening to a guided teacher um be
going back to your question on what
meditation do I teach the Insight time
meditations I have up are very much
affirmation based so like I will read
you I've got one here actually I will
read to you you know I am so much more
than my trauma what happened to me does
not define me I'm kind and gentle myself
after everything I've been through and
I'll I'll be saying these on the track
basically um and you'll be listening to
these as as you do your breaths um but
actually I don't that's not how I
meditate I don't know how I ended up
doing that I don't know what it just
obviously that's what seem to flow with
how I record um but it changes um what I
produce and I'm always evolv
so does that answer all the meditation
questions I can't remember if I oh sure
I mean it's an impossible task to answer
my questions I'm I'm a rambling man over
here so you did you did wonderfully um
yeah I I well I think with meditation
there's so many different types and
there is definitely times for different
types because I feel like I had I had a
a you know a pretty long time like
probably a good year or two where the
positive affirmations were a lot of like
I pretty much Start every morning with
that sort of thing like I was just I was
in a space where I was recognizing hey
every morning when I'm waking up my
dream world is not treating me good so
I'm starting every morning off on this
like negative mindset and I can't help
it wait I can help it as soon as I wake
up let's start just pulverizing it with
positive stuff and uh you know that's
that's not like a long-term thing but
for me at that time in my life those are
the sorts of meditations that work for
me at least for like the morning until I
can get into later on in the day and and
do different types of meditations um and
I think I I I just love everything you
said about like finding what works for
you in all the different types
because it's there's I just had this guy
in the podcast and he was talking about
um he's written 13 books and his thing
was like you know someone might ask you
know how do you write 13 books that's so
much so many words blah blah blah and he
basically broke it down as like I wrote
200 to 300 words a day and like that's
it like that's the thing and so I've
been like thinking about that a lot
since I talked to him I even wrote like
on my whiteboard 300 words a day and
it's just basically like
you can't write the whole book in one
day dude you can't reach Enlightenment
in one day you can't be the best
meditator in the world in one day if
it's your first day trying it what can
you do you know like can you get can you
get third three words today cool that's
that's better than nothing and it's and
I think finding something that actually
speaks to you instead of just like
because because for some people maybe
mindfulness just like trying to close
your eyes open your eyes and just follow
your breath so sometimes that's just not
it for people and sometimes like I think
what's important is for people to
actually have like unexperienced
that one like for newbies to meditation
just introducing them to their five
senses in like a slow you know um um
elegant like gentle way is like profound
for people they've never really slowed
down and just concentrated on a specific
sense before um for people I I think uh
breath work like doesn't have to be the
extreme Wim Hoff breathing but even just
like typ in YouTube follow along breath
meditation or go on inside timer I'm
sure there's tons of like is there is
there breath work follow along on yeah
I'm sure there's lows on there one I one
I don't do on inside tourament but my
favorite one is single nostril breathing
um just it actually completely resets
your brain and your brain breathing so
it's great for when I'm working with
people with anxiety as well can you tell
me the the trick for that for anybody
listening yeah so uh you close off you
start breathing in through your right
nostril so close off your left nostril
breathe in through your right close off
your right breathe out through your
left breathe in through the
left close off the left breathe out
through the right and it's it's that
basically but it um if you believe in
sort of the energy Concepts uh your
right nostril is your masculine and your
left is your feminine so ideally you
want to have a if you're trying to get
to sleep and you can't sleep you're
supposed to um blow air out your nose
and one of the nostrils will be stronger
than the other and you want your left
nostril to be the stronger one at night
because that's your feminine Yin Cal um
energy um so if it's in your if it's
your right nostril you're still in work
mode and you'd have a have a probably do
some journaling yeah yeah yeah you need
to get out of bed now I yeah I think uh
breathing and breath techniques are
really the ultimate I remember when I
was young I had uh I had asthma when I
was young what's funny is as I get older
start to like redefine like what what
really is asthma like I I don't know if
we fully understood I think I was just
having like panic attacks all the time
um but I remember I had an uncle I was
camping and it was like this vivid
memory cuz I was like dying from this
asthma attack I was stressing myself out
so bad I remember I was sitting against
a a truck tire of like a Ford pickup and
I was just panicking I was just couldn't
breathe crying my eyes out whatever I
was under the age of nine or something
um but what what my uncle did in that
moment is he put his hand on my chest
and uh I think he had my hand on his
chest and he basically said don't try to
stop crying don't try to start breathing
or like catch your breath just try to
sink up with my breathing and like that
was just profound I feel like it's I've
held on to it like for my whole life
like it really taught me about breathing
and um just I I just I think it's it
seems like really lwh hanging obvious
fruit to people like hey man if you're
stressed out take a breath take a deep
breath but it's really like hey you can
solve that in a way like you can stop
having a panic attack in you know not
that not trying to uh you know disregard
someone's panic attack but um becoming
in tune with your breath practicing it
in moments of calm so you're used to
your breathing and you're used to like
what to do or used to different you know
the the in in through the left nostril
out through the right nostril whatever
it is you practice those things off of
being stressed out so when those moments
come in and you do start to get amped up
you get in a panic attack whatever you
go oh I'm noticing my breath is way up
here in my throat and I'm I'm stressed
out I could relax a a little bit and
have it down to my diaphragm and that's
like such a man that's such a breath of
fresh air isn't it like when you you
realize that you can control your breath
a bit and it's really really helpful
yeah and like the power of taking a deep
belly breath because our diaphragm
doesn't get used enough and therefore
we're not using as much oxygen as we
could so we're not having as clear a
mind clear a body as we could there's so
much power in that you know yeah yeah
100% um hey so I want to talk about I I
just because I listened to the podcast
this morning your episode on basically
kind of like hey I was super depressed
and here's like some things that really
moved the needle forward for me um I
think you mentioned fasting water
fasting that's for sure I agree with
that one um that helps with eating
disorder stuff too I've dealt with those
sorts of things um you talked about I
think you did a great grapefruit fast
yeah grapefruit a great fruit juice that
I read in this book to um help my I
thought I had goals stones at the time
and I found
this I think I said it in the podcast
but I found this really old book in like
this random National Trust it's like our
country houses around here um that was
like oh this ancient remedy just drink
grapefruit juice for 3 days straight
it's all you got to eat so I did it for
this gstes thing which I was like well
maybe my G stones are negatively
affecting my energy and that's where
anger stored and maybe anger is making
me depressed so I did that and but the
theory then having researched around it
is that I think it's more impactful for
women but the pH the grapefruit when
you're only consuming grapefruit for
that amount of time um apparently it
changes like the pH of your gut I want
to say you'll have to look at the study
I shared it somewhere at one point um
from it's either acid to alkaline
alkaline to acid acidic um and if you
are one way or the other it can
influence depression something like
about 80% but in specifically in women
it doesn't I don't think it has so much
of a big effect if you're changing your
pH in men but if you're interested in
this and it hasn't been something that
you've tried looking up the pH reversal
diet or the pH diet um is is definitely
a more subtle way of doing it than just
drinking grapefruit juice for three days
yeah um I'm very much a hard and fast
gal when it comes to Quick
Fix I'm with you I sometimes I have to
just go all in sometimes I'm like cool I
I saw this remedy I'm going for it right
now we're starting now yeah yeah I think
when you're like with depression like it
does get to a point where you get so
desperate and You' still got that I want
to be better type part of yourself that
you're like I will do anything like give
me all the potential options which is
exactly what I did I just you know for
research purposes I didn't split them
out over a longer period of time so I
don't know which one it was that
actually made the big [__] right right
right well okay so so bring someone so
say someone is like look I I'm at that
point where I'm sick of not trying
anything or I want to try something else
I'm sick of being depressed I want to
I've got a weekend off of work coming up
I've got three days Friday Saturday
Sunday or you know Saturday
Sunday what what do I do what what
should I start throwing at the wall okay
so now I think there's like five things
I thrw at the wall which was the
grapefruit thing I did um I was fasting
I I think it was I think I did maybe
three days solid fast and then I was
having bits in between um of that I also
took lithium oxalate which is not the
same as lithium and people got really
grumpy with me on TI talk when I
suggested it they were like no don't say
that word yeah you can't say that so
many side effects like no lithium
oxalate is like a herbal supplement you
can buy on eBay um so that I and there's
there's some small research studies
around that as well and I actually still
if I need that now if I'm having a day
where i'm like hm I feel down and I
don't think this is to do with
psychology I think this is something
biological which for me is somebody with
hormonal challenges um I have PCOS and
my hormones are a little bit crazy crazy
um is is common for me so lithium
oxalate I take one and honestly within a
couple of hours I'm absolutely fine so
that I think works definitely from a
short-term basis for me um and please
consult your doctor first I'm not a
scientist or medical advisor um and then
probably the the big guns is magic
mushrooms and I have so much adoration
for them and I I don't know where I'd be
without magic mushrooms and you did Mega
doses right did you did like you didn't
do the micro do I didn't [__] about I
went I went hard and fast this
is um and I think I'm I can be quite
anxious around Health type things but
again because I was like so depressed I
was like [__] it they're not going to
kill me I know from research you can't
die from Madding mushrooms unless you go
and drive a car which you don't want to
when you're on them anyway you just want
to sit and stare at the ceiling um how
do you even get to your front seat if
you I couldn't even have we I was like I
don't know how to use my legs so I
rolling around on the living room floor
sounds good
though oh God yeah um so so did you did
you have intentions sorry to interrupt
did you have uh like did you go into it
with intentions um did you know like
like I'm going to take these and listen
to like this frequency on YouTube I'm
going to take these and try to meditate
I'm going to take these and like like
what did you what did you do and do you
think that matters yes so I actually
have quite strong beliefs around this
purely through experimentation from
myself and my boyfriend um I really
think you have to go in intentionally
with mushrooms otherwise they won't
serve you they want you to they want you
to do your work um and so every time
I've done them I have sat in low
lighting um calm music on Andor
meditation and all trip music playlists
are actually very good they know what
they're doing have a look on Spotify for
those fantastic stuff um and I did once
do chanting music which me to a whole
different plane I thought I was
traveling the world it was amazing um
and one time I had a bath as well um at
the early stages before I completely
lost my mind um so yeah absolutely I
think you have to be very intentional
about it I think always have a
tripsitter have somebody in the house
just in case and it's never happened to
me but just in case you do get a bit
panicky which it's ever happened to me
or anybody that I've seen do them or
trap trips that with um which I love to
do I'd love to be part of people's
experience um and then I write a list of
questions for myself on a notepad um of
what I want to try and go into and what
I want to ask Spirit why I want to ask
myself um and then what I found I don't
know if you've done it or how hard
you've gone when you've got there but
like writing is just is not going to
happen so I've managed a couple of times
to text it's like drunk texting when I
when I read it back the next day it's
like drunk texting but when you're in it
you don't feel drunk but you also do
feel drunk drunk so surreal um so I like
text myself these incredibly profound
like lifechanging notes um that I get to
see the next morning and be like wow I
really went then so that's my process
yeah nice I I think that's super helpful
um it's it's this interesting thing man
with with with psychedelics it really is
so I've done um I've also done ketamine
therapy have you done ketamine I haven't
no yeah I did ketamine therapy and the
way the girl described it I I just
really liked it um she basically said
it's like it's like a windshield wiper
like it's like cleaning your windshield
you know like doing doing ketamine or
like a a shroom trip or whatever like if
you're doing it intentionality with
intentionality for your mental health
you know or like hey I've got this thing
I notice that's been just really
plaguing me I can't seem to work through
it in my sober life so let me like
really try to attack it crisscross
applesauce with a blindfold uh taking
mushrooms um but yeah it's uh it's it's
the weirdest thing it's I'm always
trying to explain to people I wonder if
you have any good input on this is it's
like hard for people to wrap their mind
around it's not just right now it's not
just the trip like as much as you do get
these kind of like you know downloads or
profound oh wow I've been treating
myself this way and I don't need to do
that like wow that's profound whatever
but there's also like the day after the
week after the couple weeks after the
months after like uh what do you what do
you know about that like what is it how
is it still working on us like days
weeks months afterwards yeah so like the
way that it works is like you said it
wipes your brain your your the neurons
all go wee and just start again
basically and they're like right let's
figure out a new way that works better
to connect with each other um and that I
think it takes three weeks for them to
get back to um more connected so like
you can often the days after feel a bit
headachy a bit out of it a bit like
you're sing a trip even though you're
not um but I think the the podcast that
I did on that I had done that the that
was my third trip that I'd done and that
was beginning of December 2023 and I've
genuinely not been the same since I've
been structured and routine and I've not
had depressive episodes I've been like I
feel like a normal healthy functioning
human being for the first time in my
whole life rather than like the the ups
and downs that I used to have was so
like oh here we go again depressive
episode for six weeks great or like okay
okay I'm really super focused in in
terms right now like is this where's
this going to go um whereas now I'm like
consistent I'm
levelheaded um and I and genuinely like
that was the weeks after the mushroom
trip SLG grapefruit SL fasting era um
that and I just the date of it it was
just since then it's just not been same
I also did meditation group meditation
at that
same yeah yeah yeah tell me about that I
you talked about on the podcast but tell
listeners about it too you did what kind
of good meditation why was it helpful
what happened so I was working with um
alongside of psychic at the time I was
in a psychic group and I do a lot of
intuitive psychic stuff myself I do
tarot readings as well um and I went
into this group meditation and he did us
a walkthrough of basically going to see
our Spirit guides um and I'm very I'm
very connected with all that kind of
things so I found it quite easy but I
got into this space he said you know go
through the Flor in your mind you get to
the part where you see your Spirit
guides and for the first time in God
knows how long I felt loved all these
Spirit guides around me the people that
were were no longer here and the people
that were as well I could feel the
energy people that were here with me um
it was like this sudden realization that
people cared about me and that people
loved me um and that I had value and I
think definitely when you're depressed
you can think there is I you have no
worth in the world there's you know
there's no reason for you being here
nobody gives a [__] um and I literally
came out of that meditation streaming
with tears everyone in the room was like
you okay it's everything all right and I
was like whoa yes yeah like what just
happened um and I think that you know
again which is why I firmly believe like
if you're like well I'm never going to
be fixed because I'm not ever going to
do psychedelics do meditation because I
I've gotten there so many times and I
can tell you I've done mushroom trips
and I've done meditations with the right
you know set up for your meditation the
right state of mind you can absolutely
get to the same place with it yeah what
and what do you think about uh like the
group meditation effect I have found I
don't know what the heck to do with it I
know there's a lot of like Collective
unconscious um there's so many things
that play into it but every time I've
been on like a Meditation Retreat or
I've been with people who are like also
doing the same meditation I did
transcendental meditation for a while
and when I would meditate with them dude
my meditation was so much so powerful
it's like every time I'd meditate with a
group is significant I mean not every
time but a lot of times meditate with a
group is significantly more powerful
than than doing it solo do you have
experience in that do do you do you
resonate with that yeah absolutely and I
think if you find a like-minded group of
people that can be really special as
well um being in that psychic group we
would sort of we'd come up our
meditations and one of us would be like
hey did your nan come into that dream
like she was here in mine telling me
that she loves you she was she there
with you and yeah and the one was oh my
God yeah and then someone else is like
does anybody know about a pink rose
brooch and someone's like oh my God that
Happ you know it was like this just
crazy connection that we had from sort
of being in that space and having the
the energy field there yeah yeah there's
something to it I I would love to just I
in an Ideal World I would love to not
have to work and just be in a meditation
world every day I did I visited um
Fairfield Iowa is where uh Mahar um
there's a place called Maharishi
International uh University it's like
the headquarters of the transal
meditation movement and uh I I stayed
there in that town like actually in one
of their dorms for three or four days I
did like the whole tour and I I totally
love this college I actually almost went
there um but they have two giant
meditation hes like in this city on the
college campus and they I think they
hold four to five 4 or 600 a piece ones
for females ones for males and twice a
day every single day without pause
people go to those meditation domes and
they do their transcendental you know 20
to 40 minutes of meditation and then
they go home and the energy in that town
like being next to those domes is just
undeniable like I I don't even know what
to say about it like I I would sit down
to meditate by myself and I felt like I
was just like lifted up by a thousand
hands you know like it just it's it's
pretty profound so I don't know what to
do with any of that information but
clearly when you're meditating in a
group there's profound effects and it's
super cool yeah and I wish we had more
option to do it you know maybe in the
future as you become more of a
collective Society again it will become
more normal so you know living groups
and being groups and connect to our
subconscious and collective subconscious
or Collective unconscious together as
groups as well yeah I I think so I it's
it's clear that we are being pushed more
and more into like more and more people
are in t in tune with they're not so
scared by words like spirituality um
they're not so turned up I mean the
amount of the amount of like you know
right now what's going on the last
couple years is like the amount of
people that are converting and in like
becoming Christians now or they um you
know people getting into into yoga and
meditation the internet has really
opened up the possibilities for people
becoming in tune with their spiritual
side so yeah I I would it would be so
cool in the next 10 years you just start
what if that was the most normal thing
ever like your average public high
school is just like oh yeah bro we we
did meditation second period we love it
you know that'd be that'd be amazing
yeah um well hey we we are up here in
time um I I don't want to take a ton of
your time I think I had only said 90
minutes originally so um with respect to
your time as much as I could probably
ask you about a million more questions
and I think we probably talk all day
let's Round the Corner cor um anybody
listening right now I would just I'm
sure they're going to be intrigued to
like check out more of your stuff to
learn more about you uh I'll include all
the links and stuff below but can you
just tell people what you got going on
what you have available where can they
find it how should they reach out to you
um give them a Lowdown to reach out to
you yeah absolutely so my website is
Rebecca w.org and my social media is
Rebecca Wild with four a in between I am
a coach I do free meditations on insight
timer and I do tarot readings astrology
readings and I'm also this year training
as a Dueler a birth Dueler like a
virtual Dueler support as well so I'm
open for any of it but if you listen to
me and you're like Rea I think you can
help me with something else please let
me know I'm such an evolving always open
to just helping my fellow humans with
anything that you think could be
valuable um my YouTube I'm quite active
on as well as Instagram and they you
know they're all the same handle so um
yeah just I'm really loving this part of
life where I get to brunch out and and
support in different ways yeah yeah very
cool and you have your book of course do
remind me the name of your book oh yeah
my book yeah so that's H called the will
to live project and that is on Amazon
and it's really a collection of all the
little insights I've had I think I've
mentioned quite a few of them today
they're just in written format if people
prefer it that way if not you can scroll
through like loaded my Instagram post
and they're sort of dotted around there
as well it's quite a long form way of
doing it um but yeah that's my current
book and there will definitely be more
I'm a writer at heart so if you're
listening to this in like five years I'm
sure I've probably written a few more
there's one coming out this year so
there there will be more on here well I
I will say I'll will extend the branch
please hit me up next time you have a
book come out and we'll do another
podcast how about that yeah I mean Jacob
we definitely need to do another podcast
I also could keep talking I feel like we
got a lot I know it's funny I'm looking
at my notes I have and I even have
another page of notes but I I didn't
really even get to the notes I just save
them we'll do a part two I completely
I'm I'm up for that heck yeah I think we
totally should um well awesome I Rebecca
thank you so much for your time thank
you so much for following that intuition
to reach out to me originally anyway um
it's I think I told you I I force
everything to be a synchronicity
sometimes but um that same day I was
like oh yeah I need to get I'm going to
book a podcast uh guest today that was
like literally on my list of notes and
so it's just dope for you to reach out
I'm like hey I think I would be a good
fit and I look at yourself I'm like ah
perfect fit so yeah it's just it it it
works out well um so next time around um
please hit me up um listeners love
yourselves if you haven't stressed today
what are you doing stretch a little bit
if you haven't drank water drink a
little water love yourself give yourself
a big old hug right now and uh check out
Rebecca's stuff we will see you guys
next episode Rebecca thank you so much
again I appreciate your time I'll be in
touch great thank you all right
listeners have a good rest of your day
Rebecca have a good rest of your day
peace out everybody
[Music]
at what age do we learn how to have
better
conversations at what age do we learn to
have better conversations with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is
power reality is
[Music]